<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[NetMinded Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Protect your reputation and reduce operational costs by sharing status information with the right stakeholders at the right time.]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 17:22:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Why We Decided to Rebrand to Netminded]]></title><description><![CDATA[Background SeeThru Networks was started in July 2018 but the ideas behind its inception were older than that. Originally created as a…]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk/why-we-rebranded-to-netminded/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://netminded.co.uk/why-we-rebranded-to-netminded/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SeeThru Networks was started in July 2018 but the ideas behind its inception were older than that. Originally created as a vehicle so that I could do some consulting with CityFibre, and then fate intervened. Or rather Paul Anslow, CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://trianglenetworks.co.uk&quot; title=&quot;Triangle Networks Website&quot;&gt;Triangle Networks&lt;/a&gt; bought me brunch. During this excellent meal our conversations turned to some of the ideas we’d both been thinking of as we had different reasons to consider how to improve customer support. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I started in Carrier Ethernet I’ve been passionate about carriers and their partners actually using carrier Ethernet OAM correctly to share circuit status information between stakeholders. Automatically. Without NIDs being stacked upon NIDs and without customers having to call NOCs having to call NOCs having to call customers. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paul was more concerned about addressing the problem of how to share operational information with IT channel partners. Then latterly how to automate diagnostics and support of residential broadband customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I termed this co-operation between stakeholders as Mutualised Service Assurance - where everyone has the information picture they need in order to respond to service state changes in the most constructive, mutually supportive manner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, after a long brunch, Paul challenged me to build the first version of the platform so that his organisation could be the first to use it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Wider Service Assurance use cases&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So by now we have been operating SeeThru Networks for 4 years. We started building the platform a few years ago and it is now on version 3 (just about released now).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this time we have grown our use cases with our customers to consider a wider range of Service Assurance scenarios. Not just network related - but across information systems and applications that users in Enterprise, SME or at home use and consume.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Service Assurance for residential services - the information base needed from one key group of stakeholders, the customer themselves, is hard to acquire. OSS platforms can gather information to a point but the customers own platforms (Devices etc.) are outside the scope of current provider OSS. Hence my interest in working with folks like Paul Hague of &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/monster-the-trustpilot-lottery-with-cyber-assurance&quot; title=&quot;NetMinded Black Dice Article&quot;&gt;Black Dice&lt;/a&gt;. Building a net picture of the Service Assurance data in this space is a challenge currently being well funded by the investment community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Enterprise space, our partners there face a greater complexity in their operating environments. Barriers exist not just between many providers in the digital supply chain but within the provider companies themselves. Co-operating to effectively create the collective Service Assurance picture - a net information base if you prefer - is a challenge we are greatly enjoying working with our partners on in this space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;So why NetMinded&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We felt we needed to lose both “SeeThru” and particularly “Networks” as networks represented only one of our Service Assurance use cases. NetMinded is a term that to me encompasses the differences we make for our customers in their Service Assurance solutions and associated business outcomes. Net for the aggregate, the total view of all information, Mind because a NetMind is a sum of all the Minds applying themselves to a particular Service Assurance solution. So we have NetMinded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think further cooperation with your delivery partners and your customers, external or internal might be valuable to your business? Get in touch with us to discuss mutualising your Service Assurance solution.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[UK Challenger ISP? Monster the Trustpilot lottery with Cyber Assurance]]></title><description><![CDATA[As an ISP, implementing Cyber Assurance will help you capture market share by supporting your differentiated value. It will build value into…]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk/monster-the-trustpilot-lottery-with-cyber-assurance/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://netminded.co.uk/monster-the-trustpilot-lottery-with-cyber-assurance/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As an ISP, implementing Cyber Assurance will help you capture market share by supporting your differentiated value. It will build value into your headline feature set/marketing but also it will reinforce your operational excellence to help you monster the Trustpilot lottery. If you can&amp;#x27;t make the Internet simple and therefore safe for your customer, you will not win market share.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Helping broadband services to stand out from the crowd&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the big question for challenger ISPs seeking to capture market share. Speed is no longer the differentiator. Larger providers have volume pricing - so price is not a differentiator. The alt-nets - local fibre providers - wholesale services nationally to anyone - so geography is not a differentiator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, from the multitude of offers how does a customer select you as their provider?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you going to decide on a level of investment in network capacity based on the vagaries of Trustpilot algorithms/the impact of one angry customer who couldn&amp;#x27;t be satisfied if the Internet was entirely uploaded into a massive edge compute datacenter in their living room?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consumption of video via streaming services as the new norm. The new reality of working from home. The move of home automation/home IoT from novelty through niche to emerging “PC World” mainstream. This means that customers are even more demanding. The ISP is always going to be the first point of call for the residential broadband user. For everything “WiFi” related.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This more demanding customer base is increasing their reliance on the Internet and increasing their cyber attack surface in equal measure. An increasingly cyber-vulnerable customer is a threat not only to themselves but to the serving ISPs profit margin and Trustpilot rating. Arguably, the Network Operators that the serving ISP takes service from is also threatened. History shows that the air-gap provided by the serving ISP is not a 100% guarantee of insulation for the Network Operator from reputational damage caused by poor customer service experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Changing demand creates opportunity&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;These challenging market conditions are offset somewhat by some positive changes in market demand that the alternative (alternative to the “big 5”) UK ISPs can seek to exploit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internet (or “WiFi”) is now a basic staple. See some of the commentary from unfortunate Ukranians caught up in the war of Russian aggression. They mention food, water, shelter and Internet access in the same sentence, in every interview. In the UK and other developed markets, Covid has accelerated this move from luxury/nice-to-have to now considering Internet access as a basic staple of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As this new basic staple - Fibre has now penetrated the customer consciousness as the Internet product to have. In the UK - the lack of fibre availability/uptake means that alongside Germany - the UK represents the best market opportunity in Europe for fibre broadband providers. BT at Broadband World Forum 2021 estimated that EU fibre rollout will double, and UK multiply by 4 times by 2025. Investment in Fibre access networks is massive and shows no signs of slowing down. Lots of residential customers will be changing Internet technologies and could be very open to sales/marketing approaches from a new provider.
Lack of triple play service “bundles” for new or challenger providers may not be an issue. Customers are increasingly changing their buying habits  - they are more resistant to built in or in their terms hidden benefits that they don&amp;#x27;t need. The economic situation will amplify this trend. This allows challenger ISPs to captise on the fact that they don&amp;#x27;t have those built in video services…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customers also want a more transparent, immediate relationship with their ISP. They don&amp;#x27;t want to wait ages on a telephone support line - to be told basic information. Innovation in localised, self service, automated, fully transparent and support relationships with effective real-time communications are an opportunity for the challenger ISP. SeeGiffGaff’s user feedback.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;So how does cyber assurance help the challenger ISP and their Network Provider?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working with Paul Hague at Black Dice I think we have both moved from our initial thoughts on simply adding an important new cybersecurity feature to the challenger ISP service offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I first met Paul at the NCSCs Cyber Security Accelerator at Cheltenham. The feature set of Black Dice really resonated with me as a parent of Internet-using teenage children. Since then the addition of device fingerprinting/home network security etc has been something I’ve kept a close eye on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While these cyber security features are important to end users, I believe the cyber monitoring functionality from Black Dice also has an important part to play in customer support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we move to further automate customer service delivery and to further enable customer self service, actionable information is key. Cyber Assurance data from Black Dice empowers customers to self service in terms of their own individual cyber security. It has a wealth of cyber security features that are documented &lt;a href=&quot;https://blackdice.io/quantum/&quot; title=&quot;Black Dice Website&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. But it also provides a wealth of information about customer experience and the customer home network environment.  When added to things like the TR069 data model, cyber assurance data massively helps the ISP to troubleshoot complex home environment issues. Ultimately - we will automate this troubleshooting to further reduce the reliance of the end user on the ISP help desk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Differentiate your residential broadband services with Cyber Assurance&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are a challenger ISP I hope that this article has given you some ideas about how cyber assurance not only adds a vital service for you end users but also underpins your efforts to differentiate your brand from your competitors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to explore the topics introduced in this article, reach out to either Paul Hague or myself (or indeed both of us!) and we’d gladly discuss these issues further with you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[First Contact Resolution Metrics — Justify Investment in I.T. Ops]]></title><description><![CDATA[Techies! First Contact Resolution Metrics (FCR) are your friend! So you are a tech support advocate in your organisation. Or maybe you are…]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk/first-contact-resolution-metrics/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://netminded.co.uk/first-contact-resolution-metrics/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Techies! First Contact Resolution Metrics (FCR) are your friend!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you are a tech support advocate in your organisation. Or maybe you are in product management. Why are First Contact Resolutions metrics a useful set of measurements to help you get the investment in IT monitoring systems you are looking for. To get that investment signed off by your leadership team? Read on — and discuss!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Our recent introduction to FCR&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SeeThru came into being around a central passion — that tech support can be improved through better team work. Teaming up with your own colleagues, with your suppliers, with your peer organisations and above all with your customers. The question is how do you create information/process environments to enable this team work?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working with our early adopter customers — the greatest impact and biggest need we address has been that axis of 1st line support/customer communication. I follow folks in this area who I think we need to listen to. One such chap is Peter Massey from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.budd.uk.com/&quot; title=&quot;Budd Website&quot;&gt;Budd UK&lt;/a&gt;. It was on a call with Peter and his peers in the contact centre industry that I originally heard the term “First Contact Resolution’’. It just clicked for me that this was something we could help with. Indeed it was exactly this problem we had been focusing on for the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What is “First Contact Resolution”? What does it mean for tech support?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be fair — this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bmc.com/blogs/first-contact-resolution-for-improved-customer-satisfaction&quot; title=&quot;BMC Blog&quot;&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt; from Joe Hertvik of BMC was the best bit of research I came up with. For our purposes — I disagree with Joe on one point; it is the equation for “Gross” FCR that I think our customers and ourselves will find most useful. Thus Joe describes;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net FCR = Support issues resolved on the 1st contact / (All incoming call tickets — all incoming tickets that cannot be resolved at level one)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we focus on this then I would say that this is something of a cop out. Our customer experience is allowed to be impacted because our systems of work/ of monitoring are not very good at allowing customers calls to be dealt with by our 1st line support team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The simpler equation for Gross FCR would probably lead to a higher standard of customer satisfaction with our 1st line support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gross FCR = Support issues resolved on the 1st contact / All incoming support requests.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;How can a focus on Gross FCR help?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customers want one thing — that the thing you sell them just works. No issues. However — as a bad second best — they don’t want to have to call you when it does go wrong. If they do have to call you — they want it to be a quick and painless experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one of our team said just the other day, often you get better information about your Deliveroo order for a takeaway meal than you get from your ISP when your Internet is down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Gross FCR we are measuring our organisation’s ability to handle the call request in one go. That means we don’t have the luxury of ignoring escalations required to 2nd line customer support our metrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That means we can measure the value of investment in automation and working practices that;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allows 2nd line teams to automate diagnostics for 1st line support — because if 1st line handles the complete problem set — then Gross FCR improves.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allows our 2nd line teams expertise to automate diagnostics and communication to end users. Because — if they don’t call because they don’t need to — then Gross FCR improves.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Empowers our 1st line team to diagnose and flag issues where our automation has failed to meet an end user use case. The more we improve the 1st line diagnostic environment — the better our metrics.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last point is increasingly important in a world where help desks struggle with recruitment and retainment.Recruitment because there is often no visible career path in the 1st line support itself. Retention because 1st line support in tech organisations is typically seen as a right of passage for a techy wanting to progress on their technical career. Such technical members of staff are encouraged to get qualifications and experience and then move on and “upwards”. The future contact centre — and the role of the people staffing it are worth considering for organisations that need to compete based on their customers’ experience of their service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;In summary, Gross FCR helps organisations target CX outcomes with their IT investment&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monitoring your systems properly. Putting the monitoring data into tools driven by machine learning or A.I. to drive better diagnostics. Taking the time to build automated data sharing interfaces with partners. How is this investment properly justified against the big picture? Perhaps this is not just about making techies lives easier. Which is where too often the conversation on IT monitoring stops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This investment in looking after and listening to I.T. systems can also drive up customer experience. Such investment can reduce the number of support calls and improve the speed of resolution for received support calls. This effect can be measured and the measurement is called (Gross) First Contact Resolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To discuss this with us, to hear about how we are automating customer contact, customer self service and empowering 1st line support teams to resolve customer queries 1st time then get in touch with us!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[SeeThru Launches Support Tools and Brandable App for ISPs and MSPs]]></title><description><![CDATA[SeeThru Networks, the Bristol-based network and service assurance experts have launched their new dashboard and white-label app for end…]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk/support-tools-brandable-product/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://netminded.co.uk/support-tools-brandable-product/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;SeeThru Networks, the Bristol-based network and service assurance experts have launched their new dashboard and white-label app for end users to self-diagnose connectivity issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app, downloadable from Google Play or the Apple App Store, turns complex network and connectivity status messages into simple red, amber, green traffic light colours for end users to easily see if there’s an issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Support Teams can message users through the app to let them know they’re aware of problems and update them as issues are fixed which avoids customers calling, emailing, opening support tickets or taking to social media to complain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dashboard, designed for ISP and MSP Support Teams shows customers internet, network and service statuses in one panel to reduce first contact resolution times. Support Teams can remotely run connection and speed tests which factor the device, router and network capacity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Already integrated with Cisco Meraki, HP Aruba, UniFi, Vantage Cloud, Open NMS, PRTG, Observium, UpTimeRobot and Zabbix, the dashboard and app are in use by ISPs, MSPs and even venue-tech providers to reduce complex issues to easily understandable output.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customisable for virtually any application or service and fully brandable, the app can be used to convey service messages, planned outages alerts and issue resolution updates, whilst maintaining corporate brand colours, logos and fonts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CEO of SeeThru Networks, Nick Randall said about the product launch: “Customer expectations for service updates are being reset by the likes of Deliveroo and UberEats. ISPs and their partner MSPs need to respond by providing customers with easy to understand information in real-time. Customers want to self-diagnose problems and receive updates without wasting their time and the customer support time with basic problems.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Triangle and FibreHop CEO Paul Anslow commented: “The SeeThru platform gives the Fibrehop team access to real-time network usage and status information. This enables us to pinpoint customer connection issues to the exact location of the fault and resolve issues quickly and effectively. By providing our customers with access to the same information via the app, we are able to offer a uniquely transparent customer experience which reduces inbound support calls.”&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 reasons why Ethernet Connectivity Fault Management saves time and money]]></title><description><![CDATA[My Carrier Ethernet background goes back a long way. First with early packet ring start-ups Dynarc and Native Networks (acquired by Alcatel…]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk/ethernet-connectivity-fault-management/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://netminded.co.uk/ethernet-connectivity-fault-management/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My Carrier Ethernet background goes back a long way. First with early packet ring start-ups Dynarc and Native Networks (acquired by Alcatel). Then with Hatteras, Overture and for a good few years- Accedian Networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My relationship with Accedian was rekindled from the outside recently. SeeThru has been engaged in the roll out the first Ethernet peering point for a new residential ISP brand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This ISP takes access network connectivity from one of the UKs leading fibre providers. Of course the layer 1 tech is G-PON but the Ethernet is Carrier Ethernet “lite” all the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First we integrated systems, then tested and now have live customers on the network. I found it interesting watching my colleagues get first hand operational experience of Ethernet Connectivity Fault Management (CFM). Particularly in how it enriches the cross organisational visibility of Ethernet circuits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was also reminded of how Carrier Ethernet and CFM in particular is a real mystery to battle hardened, experienced IP network professionals. So this article is for them — and maybe a reminder to folks like me. Here are my recently re-learned top 5 reasons to consider adding Ethernet CFM to your network monitoring/network diagnostic strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;1. You haven’t got IP endpoints to ping in all the places you need them&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;These networks are made up of Local Access, Regional and National Ethernet from multiple providers. These circuits are not leased lines with IPs to ping away at. Having Ethernet Maintenance association End Points (MEPs) at each interface allows verification of connectivity segment by segment. Concurrently and securely, by all cooperating partners and providers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2. There are whole load of new logical interfaces to misconfigure&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through user network interface, network to network interfaces (access/distribution and distribution/core) and of course external network to network interfaces there are lots of places to get your tags, Ethertypes and PCP markings all set up properly. And plenty of time for long phone calls while everyone insists their side is set up properly. CFM — and dare I say it an “open” platform like SeeThru to share it on — helps get to the bottom of all of this really quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;3. Residential broadband customers have another box to turn off&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a new box on your customers’ site and it needs both power and the RJ45 cable from your supplied router/their own router to be in the right port. Running Connectivity Check Messages across the Layer 2 network to the (forward thinking) wholesale carrier’s ONT will give you live status of this — and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;4. Ethernet performance monitoring is built into your kit&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yep, “free” stuff is cool. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/ios-xml/ios/cether/configuration/xe-3s/ce-xe-3s-book/ce-cfm-nsnhsby-xe.html&quot; title=&quot;Cisco Website&quot;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.juniper.net/documentation/en_US/junos/topics/topic-map/cfm-configuring.html&quot; title=&quot;Juniper Website&quot;&gt;Juniper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://infocenter.nokia.com/public/7750SR140R4/topic/com.sr.servicesoverview/html/services_config.html&quot; title=&quot;Nokia Website&quot;&gt;Nokia&lt;/a&gt; — these manufacturers, and others, have well developed CFM stacks in their software. Specialist Carrier Ethernet equipment providers like our partner/our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;https://accedian.com/solutions/mobile-backhaul-monitoring-service-demarcation-slas/&quot; title=&quot;Accedian Website&quot;&gt;Accedian&lt;/a&gt; have bolt-on solutions with extra smarts as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this rich toolset built in — it is well worth learning about and building a strategy to deploy the CFM toolset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;5. Automated diagnostics between wholesale network providers and their retail partners saves everyone time and money&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have used terms like “forward thinking”, “diagnostics” and “strategy” in this article. The approach by the standards bodies in this area (MEF, ITU, IEEE) with Y.1731 and 802.1ag has been consistent. That is to enable carriers and customers to collaborate on an Ethernet infrastructure. The tools were built to automate a collaborative approach to diagnostics, with information sharing intrinsic to the architectures and protocols. Even with a basic MEP configured for the ISP on the ONT, by their serving wholesale access network carrier, goes a long long way to reducing unnecessary phone calls between NOCs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn more about a CFM strategy for your organisation — or indeed something even closer to our hearts like automating a collective diagnostic environment — please feel free to get in touch. If transparency in service delivery is something that you share a belief in — that you also think saves everyone time and money — then we’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Powering Business-Led Innovation in a Disrupted World]]></title><description><![CDATA[New collaborative IT services thanks to our Innovate UK grant award We are very pleased to announce that out of the 8,600 applicants, our…]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk/powering-business-led-innovation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://netminded.co.uk/powering-business-led-innovation/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New collaborative IT services thanks to our Innovate UK grant award&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are very pleased to announce that out of the 8,600 applicants, our application was one of 800 proposals to be funded by Innovate UK’s Fast Start Competition. This competition forms part of the UK Government support for small businesses as a result of the disruption caused by the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Whats does this mean for SeeThru, our technology partners and their customers?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For SeeThru we get to build our team and deliver our vision of a new approach to service delivery a little more quickly. We will be even more useful right at a point where changes in the work place are crying out for a rethink in the way we technologists support smaller businesses. Providing more joined up support for small businesses as they transform using digital platforms in these extremely challenging times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For our partners we know that up to and beyond 50% of the support calls they might receive can be for issues that result from services provided by other tech providers. Think E-PoS solutions in a retail environment and how an under-pressure shop owner might call their E-PoS till provider when in fact there is an issue with local WiFi, or Internet connectivity. How does the non-technical business owner get a clear view of what is going on?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By helping digital service providers collaborate to communicate status of services to mutual end user customers — we reduce costs for everyone in the supply chain. The time spent talking to a technical help desk as they explain that the issue lies not with them but with another application provider. A scenario that wastes time for everyone, creates unnecessary friction between customer and provider — which in turn drives up churn. A cycle of waste that drives up costs — both hidden and direct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our partners for this project will directly oversee our road map funded by this grant between now and September 2020. They supply technology to Tele-medicine users in the NHS both at a Trust and at a GP surgery level. In addition, they include Internet and IT suppliers working together supporting small businesses. Our partners also represent the high street in the form of Business Improvement Districts. All of these partners are involved in strategic areas with a massively increasing dependence on technology as the Covid-19 pandemic continues to disrupt daily life. Technology that will no doubt be a key platform to enable the post Covid-19 recovery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In conclusion — Innovate UK and our partners have shown great faith in our proposal and we are looking forward to repaying that trust. There were many fine proposals from dynamic, innovative companies that were unfortunately not funded this time around. We are determined and will deliver the positive outcomes for our partners and their customers identified in our project plan.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Seeing Thru Zabbix]]></title><description><![CDATA[A low cost customer visualisation solution for technology providers The problem with visualising data for end users, when there isn’t any…]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk/seeing-thru-zabbix/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://netminded.co.uk/seeing-thru-zabbix/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A low cost customer visualisation solution for technology providers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The problem with visualising data for end users, when there isn’t any data to visualise.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As SeeThru grows we are expanding our customer base into new market segments with differing use cases. We have conversations where tech providers want to simplify the conversation with their end users — a big tick for SeeThru. But they haven&amp;#x27;t yet built management platforms that create the information for us to visualise. Yes — this is outside our happy-so-far hunting ground of ISP and IT partners where such management tools are their stock-in-trade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Fixing the foundations&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Luckily there are a great many fantastic tools to implement network and system level monitoring. Some are open source, others have great ‘freemium’ or low cost entry points. With such a competitive, long standing market place, the top solutions are all very good. Because we were not picking sides in this fight — after a quick evaluation process we recommended our client try &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zabbix.com&quot; title=&quot;Zabbix Website&quot;&gt;Zabbix&lt;/a&gt; as one suitable fit for their requirement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The customer use case&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our customer has many customer sites each with a varied deployment of IP networking endpoints. Each solution requires the co-operation of 3rd party suppliers such as WiFi LAN providers, ISPs etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enabling our customer to co-ordinate with these suppliers in front of their mutual customer is our use case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Testing the solution&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The happy thing about Zabbix for SeeThru is its specific feature “Services”. Initially we deployed a central server and built a Zabbix proxy on the ever dependable Raspberry Pi. Putting the Pi in our lab environment we created a service “SeeThru Lab availability” with a whole bunch of suitable dependencies for the overall “ok” or “not ok” signal from Zabbix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;max-width:868px&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/e62c586cf395ff31c31712beb33a7035/748b0/NetMinded_Zabbix_Service.png&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom:75.33333333333333%;position:relative;bottom:0;left:0;background-image:url(&amp;#x27;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAPCAIAAABr+ngCAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAABl0lEQVQoz31S2Y7bMAzM/39kgW0uW7YkSxQvHVZhO7sp0qSDeeCDhhwNebrcp+t9Goy93M35ZgZjrzczGns3dpzcbZgud/Pr6/r7MpjJJ2RI9MMTJBTNgGxn5+d5nq3zgUU0F9UsqqKZWIhFREupf/OkmnvvJJW8y4v1zhNzKSXnXGstpdQd/R1Osot77wHA+mWeZmOmafZhgVrbrq+ttXVd34lFjyql5L03k/VLAIAQMEZATDlr/4CH7d47MyOiiCASEQFAQgQmEEIW52OMiYgQ8ecXJ/6eHAEjYEophOiWCAmPp0BIKoftF/MnEtmUVNDOOFyn2YUQY4zlGznn1tqHwCQfLUWEmYmImWWjICLvUBFVFZGjnaoeTZ9pE4m1DhBJRGv5NO19YK210TjnXIyRlOu6reeB3ne+rus5OSEBJBEhFdqt5pL/P/+Zdin1fB2HYQghzBA8xMSEwpxVSkbdmkrJ78UJt/tt21HVdd1Mt7W19XFbbW2l1bq2F7EclUj+Og/jOIYYJlgWTCgcOaHycSr/2v4Dy+Fp/v+w3U0AAAAASUVORK5CYII=&amp;#x27;);background-size:cover;display:block&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;NetMinded Zabbix Service&quot; title=&quot;NetMinded Zabbix Service&quot; src=&quot;/static/e62c586cf395ff31c31712beb33a7035/748b0/NetMinded_Zabbix_Service.png&quot; srcSet=&quot;/static/e62c586cf395ff31c31712beb33a7035/5a46d/NetMinded_Zabbix_Service.png 300w,/static/e62c586cf395ff31c31712beb33a7035/0a47e/NetMinded_Zabbix_Service.png 600w,/static/e62c586cf395ff31c31712beb33a7035/748b0/NetMinded_Zabbix_Service.png 868w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 868px) 100vw, 868px&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once we had the service established we interacted with the very comprehensive Zabbix API to extract the “ok/not ok” status. Overall it took about an hours work our side to translate the Zabbix output to a “Red/Green” signal for the SeeThru platform to disseminate. Pulling the plug on one of our pieces of lab kit gave us the satisfying result illustrated below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;max-width:1024px&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/c80484e385642e21270fd1248e3cc9aa/2bef9/NetMinded_Service_Error_State.png&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom:83%;position:relative;bottom:0;left:0;background-image:url(&amp;#x27;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAARCAIAAABSJhvpAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAAB8ElEQVQ4y4WSa2/TMBSG++sQaP+RDxNj4yZEKTChadOYEEigwrRVtE2v5GInzsXxJY5jO0ZppaiFLRw9H6z3+JEtH/dGSzBZ+j7KYcr+AqQUpPTfHKYsiIkb5b2LaX4zXf9agQjzMGNbQEaijOdYZVjCjLb5lggzH+UuynuV0luUNi3WWKaKIb+di3WtaqWq3a7SRmsjtenZnaptba2Vtfwpbvr0dCydM3Z5XY3b1m4Za++QvxbfP/EvUEWgCgfF+Y/bJ3Y5bhr1nm/qfdlaW9Xqgl9N5bxPPhziZ0/Jay2FPT20GNl9f0/eHks0fUs+nvHLx/joFXv/Mn6hR5/t+XMreJfc+ljjOZt5LAACAeLJ6bXKE9tx7W3OinK8DnyYrMOyFMpUxuhaWcuFkFVl7pebRoCywdXw28gZupQwvinGKcU5IVw0I+x4MCFVxso4oxGEXhB6PnQ94CwXPkRRxnlZdcm0kCAhMKVzLx4vwGQJZ264RgnchEx0ykxImDE3xAsvnq5C5zdagXQNUxil/5dpIYOERJihjLog8WDqx1mICcIsSAgtZJdcVjpnApES5mVEZEjKMG/WiJQ5E2Wl75XNZhCT2Dw44gcn/OFxw8FJw6NjPktNu+fOH9YUKeuBo/pT9WZDf8M7RxFZt3ta+Q+Q8sOaITcmCAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&amp;#x27;);background-size:cover;display:block&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;NetMinded Service Error State&quot; title=&quot;NetMinded Service Error State&quot; src=&quot;/static/c80484e385642e21270fd1248e3cc9aa/2bef9/NetMinded_Service_Error_State.png&quot; srcSet=&quot;/static/c80484e385642e21270fd1248e3cc9aa/5a46d/NetMinded_Service_Error_State.png 300w,/static/c80484e385642e21270fd1248e3cc9aa/0a47e/NetMinded_Service_Error_State.png 600w,/static/c80484e385642e21270fd1248e3cc9aa/2bef9/NetMinded_Service_Error_State.png 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Its getting easier to communicate service information to end users&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The out of the box experience with Zabbix is no doubt repeatable with other solutions. Using these platforms it is a fairly straightforward job for a tech provider to illustrate the overall status of a service to your end users. Mashing systems together is of course the enduring appeal of APIs!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zabbix and all terms associated with it of course are the property of that organisation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Testing our API with Carrier Ethernet NIDs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Monitoring a Carrier Ethernet circuit and representing its live status on the SeeThru app Our newly created API and Python environment…]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk/testing-our-api-carrier-ethernet-nids/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://netminded.co.uk/testing-our-api-carrier-ethernet-nids/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring a Carrier Ethernet circuit and representing its live status on the SeeThru app&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our newly created API and Python environment needed a test beyond meeting our own internal needs. Conveniently, just after we completed version one of our external feeds API, I was meeting friends in London who work at Accedian. Having some excellent Accedian Carrier Ethernet NIDs in our kit bag we hatched a plan. To test our API and have a ready explanation to my friends of “what I was up to”, we would integrate a feed from the NIDs illustrating the service status of an Ethernet circuit. Easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Building an Accedian test setup&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;max-width:831px&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/de75d6a25a56893f236bf579bc7bf47d/5adf0/NetMinded_Accedian_Equipment.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom:82%;position:relative;bottom:0;left:0;background-image:url(&amp;#x27;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAQABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwAAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQFAv/EABYBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAv/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABRxbVxZRaD//EABoQAAIDAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAgMhEhP/2gAIAQEAAQUCdLPFnEkTiW14oZ//xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEf/aAAgBAwEBPwGI/8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABIB/9oACAECAQE/AaVr/8QAGhAAAgIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQMSIycf/aAAgBAQAGPwK0bIoprgso/8QAGxAAAwACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERIVFBgbH/2gAIAQEAAT8hhvPB27RsYpbRbxEyrFopCcI//9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABDcH//EABYRAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEf/aAAgBAwEBPxCmH//EABYRAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQIf/aAAgBAgEBPxAWQ//EABwQAQADAQEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAEAETEhQWFxgf/aAAgBAQABPxC0RFul0/JSWKgLHHHI4E8sGWt1DyPrsRgXorX88xlN0D2p/9k=&amp;#x27;);background-size:cover;display:block&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;Accedian Equipment&quot; title=&quot;Accedian Equipment&quot; src=&quot;/static/de75d6a25a56893f236bf579bc7bf47d/5adf0/NetMinded_Accedian_Equipment.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;/static/de75d6a25a56893f236bf579bc7bf47d/f93b5/NetMinded_Accedian_Equipment.jpg 300w,/static/de75d6a25a56893f236bf579bc7bf47d/b4294/NetMinded_Accedian_Equipment.jpg 600w,/static/de75d6a25a56893f236bf579bc7bf47d/5adf0/NetMinded_Accedian_Equipment.jpg 831w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 831px) 100vw, 831px&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We built a back-to-back setup between two Accedian MetroNID TEs. Configuration was limited to a quick and easy L2 PAA monitoring session between the two devices. SNMP access was configured and that was it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Setting up the SeeThru feed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using pysnmp it was straightforward enough to read the SNMP database object that would tell us if there was a continuity alert between the two devices. Evaluating the continuity check and labelling it appropriately “red” or “green”, we now had a simple test of our API and a nice way for me to illustrate to my friends what we were doing with the SeeThru platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Takes an acdPaaStatusCcAlert value and evaluates RAG based on some context.
def evaluateStatusFromCcStatusValue(value):
    if (value === &amp;quot;1&amp;quot;):
        return [&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;There is a CC alert.&amp;quot;];
    elif (value === &amp;quot;2&amp;quot;):
        return [&amp;quot;green&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;There is no CC alert.&amp;quot;];
    else:
        return [&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Could not connect to the SNMP feed or locate a CC alert.&amp;quot;];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Running the demo&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plan being simple enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Meet friends — get them to buy coffee&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Show SeeThru app and proudly explain how it works&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Point out to friends the Accedian test reference.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remote into lab, disable the “far end” PAA session on one of the NIDs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exclaim “da dah!” as the Accedian test went Red on my phone as the Continuity Check alarmed out.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Actual demo&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;It was late in the day — no one could take any more coffee&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The physical environment meant that the active demo was me calling the development team and asking them to pull the cable out.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The demo of course worked perfectly thereafter and my friends were patiently gracious enough to say all the nice things that friends do in such circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;max-width:640px&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/aac373999fc89e5f73e4593df87decbd/c08c5/NetMinded_Legacy_App_Screenshot.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom:136%;position:relative;bottom:0;left:0;background-image:url(&amp;#x27;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAbABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAABAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIBBAX/xAAUAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAB/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAH0I6NCGllOJYH/xAAbEAACAgMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIREBIhMf/aAAgBAQABBQJixVx1Jcds2Z7lH//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACAh/9oACAEDAQE/AaP/xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARIP/aAAgBAgEBPwEj/8QAFxAAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAxMP/aAAgBAQAGPwJwmH//xAAdEAACAwACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAhMRBBUWFx/9oACAEBAAE/ITStQkWKXk7wAAde4LWC+zAIrDB0GM2MPGJ//9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABAkATD/xAAWEQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABIEH/2gAIAQMBAT8QXDH/xAAWEQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABESD/2gAIAQIBAT8QVcf/xAAdEAEBAAIDAAMAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAhMVFhEIHw/9oACAEBAAE/EHgIbVJfq4Kxhs/C4bM34dFMuYuwrgFBkzj6DzA8BfM5jXN1veSfB//Z&amp;#x27;);background-size:cover;display:block&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;NetMinded Legacy App&quot; title=&quot;NetMinded Legacy App&quot; src=&quot;/static/aac373999fc89e5f73e4593df87decbd/c08c5/NetMinded_Legacy_App_Screenshot.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;/static/aac373999fc89e5f73e4593df87decbd/f93b5/NetMinded_Legacy_App_Screenshot.jpg 300w,/static/aac373999fc89e5f73e4593df87decbd/b4294/NetMinded_Legacy_App_Screenshot.jpg 600w,/static/aac373999fc89e5f73e4593df87decbd/c08c5/NetMinded_Legacy_App_Screenshot.jpg 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;In conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We found that the SeeThru API for extending our feeds to external monitors worked as expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good friends are always there to nod patiently with wry smiles on their faces when you proudly show them your new “baby”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please note that this exercise was completely independent of any arrangement or involvement with Accedian. However I will point out that, in my opinion, every practising network techie would do well to have at least one Accedian MetroNID in their lab setup. They are so useful.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Toothbrush Test]]></title><description><![CDATA[Getting End User Attention Before I.T. Goes Wrong The problem is that technology is S.E.P. The toothbrush test, of the famous Larry Page…]]></description><link>https://netminded.co.uk/the-toothbrush-test/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://netminded.co.uk/the-toothbrush-test/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting End User Attention Before I.T. Goes Wrong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The problem is that technology is S.E.P.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The toothbrush test, of the famous Larry Page quote, suggests levels of end user commitment to a platform, tool, application or “thing”. The analogy being that the “thing” passing the test is something they use or engage with at least once or twice a day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For end users, technology is one of those issues categorised as “somebody else’s problem”. Naturally, getting our end users interested in the day to day of the collective value we deliver is a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a techie and being around startups quite a lot of the time, I see a lot of really cool tech things that you look at and think, despite the level of techie coolness, this thing is just not going to pass the toothbrush test for the average end user.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Why should we care?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We should care because there is a lot of value being created by IT technologists that goes unrecognised because the UI results in end users that never engage heart and soul.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without end user engagement projects, initiatives and companies just wither away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Why we should really care!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The internet technology community should really care — should really get its act together — because our end users are on a journey of what’s often called “digital transformation”. But they are on this journey without the correct tools and little training. They carry a whole load of unrealistic service expectations and price points resulting from decades of low up-front cost services and platforms. Which frustrates most technology providers I know. Including me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that digital transformation has made the internet and cloud services critical to most aspects of consumer and business daily life — expectations of service level vs. value are not often met on either the supplier or end user side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What should we do?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need to create our platforms with value propositions and user interfaces designed with the toothbrush test (for our end users) in mind. We need users to get actively engaged with their IT choices of platforms, providers, investment and risks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But we also need to make the UX convenient, understandable and commensurate with a level of attention we might reasonably expect if we imagined our end user’s daily existence. Graphs of data, pie charts and a fantastic ability to create custom reports of more data in more graphs — perhaps that isn’t always the answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Pass the toothbrush test together&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We all recognise of course that we need to build platforms that grab and keep our end users’ attention. So, having UX skills in your team is ever more critical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But — we also need to aggregate our collective value so that end users who consume services from different platforms and providers can interface in one common space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s build those supplier partnerships, work together and help instrument the information technology space in a way that suits our end users. Suits their ability to understand the significance of IT data and their willingness to spend time on the subject. Before IT goes wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At SeeThru we are building a platform to aggregate the visualization of the entire digital supply chain for end users. It’s our view that this transparency will build collective value for all. We want the monitoring of IT to pass the toothbrush test.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>